Guide to the John Bryant economics papers, 2013-2016 UA 422
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
John Bryant economics papers
2013-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Bryant, John
UA 422
0.75 Linear Feet 2 boxes
The John Bryant economics papers provide a sneak peek into the inner workings of the economics classroom at Rice University. Ranging from introductory classes to high-level graduate theory, Bryant's class notes cover a number of topics.
Biographical / Historical
John Bryant is a Professor Emeritus at Rice University. Before joining the Rice economics faculty, Professor Bryant earned a PhD from Carnegie Mellon, and worked for several branches in the Federal Reserve system. His areas of expertise include banking, and monetary theory and coordination, and his research interests include economics, epistemological and ontological foundations, coordination, asymmetric information, and strategic uncertainty.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains class notes used by John Bryant in teaching economics courses at Rice university--at the undergraduate and graduate level--as well as notes, handouts, and worksheets relevant to specific economics topics and classes. The materials are in good condition and range in date from 2013 to 2016 (though Bryant likely used the same materials for even older classes). Researchers interested in teaching at Rice and the economics department would find this collection insightful.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Tye materials were donated by John Bryant in December of 2019.
Index Terms
Subjects
Economics; Education
Document Types
lecture notes; books
Places
Rice University
Subjects (Persons)
Bryant, John
- Series I: General Class Papers
  - Economics Class Handouts, ca. 2013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class Notes: Undergraduate-level Macroeconomics (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class Notes: Undergrad Teaching Material (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class Notes: Graduate-level Macroeconomics (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Specific Topics
  - Class Notes: Government Irrelevance (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Class Notes: Overlapping Generations Model (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Class Notes: Simple Rational Expectations Keynes-type Model (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Monograph 12: "Social Choice and Individual Values" by Kenneth J. Arrow (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Class Notes: State Contingent Claims (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series III: Specific Classes
  - Class Notes: Economics 303, Fall, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Class Notes: Economics 355, Fall 2015 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Class Notes: Economics 455, Fall, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Class Notes: Economics 355, Spring, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Class Notes: Economics 203, Spring, 2016 (Box 2, Folder 5)